Welcome in to Free Agency Fridays. We
are here in the Big Bear AI Command
Center Studio for a special next man up.
Right next to me is Cale Von Chase. Boy,
I can say that name a million times.
>> I had your little vibe,
>> bro. Welcome, man. Congratulations, man.
How you feeling?
>> I feel great, man. I feel great. I
appreciate it.
>> Yeah, man. How big was this moment for
you, man? I've seen, you know, you've
you've had a few stops in your career,
especially for a first round pick, but
this one feel a little different, man.
Especially that dollar sign.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. No, it's huge, man.
It's huge. Um, obviously, man, coming
off a phenomenal year, man. Um, didn't
get a chance to seal the deal like I
wanted to, but um, a lot of things have
been moving in the right trajectory of
my career. So, um, getting a chance to
be a part of this, man, continue the the
rebuilding phase, but I honestly I just
really say putting the final touches on
something that that that really has been
already been progressing. So, um, I
think it's it's hella dogs all over the
team, man. Um, I continue want to be
that be that guy. um to be that missing
piece that's obviously put us in the
right sent us in the right trajectory.
So um with Dan Quinn, um Dvonte Jones,
man, Coach Hennessy, PGs, um man, great
guys with great energy, great
personalities, man. Um I think it's
everything and more for my career and
for this team for sure.
>> And this is a big move for your career,
man. Why the commanders? You mentioned
the coaching staff. Was it just that or
were you hearing things around the
league? Cuz everybody that sits here
just says, "Man, we heard this is the
place to be." Is that what you heard as
well?
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, most definitely. Um,
obviously, man, getting a chance to to
to to overview um everything, man. When
I was kind of mapping it out, man, this
division, man, is first to me, bro. Um,
none but talent in this division,
especially up front in the trenches. Um,
you know, you're going to go against
some great guys. Um, you know, you're
going to get the televised games. Um,
for sure. And um I think that was
everything and more that this team um
can ask for for sure when you talking
about moving in that right direction and
going and going you know to to the big
bowl and to the big game and trying to
bring home the so um I was super excited
being part of that man obviously man
Jaden man LSU guy you know man that's an
elite talent second in us so um I
believe in him I believe he'll keep us
keep us going in the right direction um
and it's everything and more man getting
a chance to be in DC for sure, bro. And
understand the the the culture and the
love that comes with it, man. All we
missing is a ring for sure. Like that's
everything, bro. Oh, we missing the ring
in this city going crazy. So, I want to
be a part of it for sure,
>> man. I love that. And being a Texas boy,
I got to imagine it's going to be fly to
beat up on the Cowboys twice a year,
right? I got to imagine you going to
like that a little bit.
>> So, I got a chance to do that when I was
I was in Jacksonville. I got a chance to
do the Texans like that a little bit
last year. I knocked them out the
playoffs and now this year I get to do
the Cowboys and send them on about their
way. So, um, hate to be the spoiler like
that to my own town. But, man, it is
what it is. It have to be that way, you
know.
>> Yeah, for sure, man. And what a journey
you've had, especially for a first round
pick, you know, highs, lows, but last
year was a high. Last year was your
career year, I believe. Seven and a half
sacks. What went right for you last
year,
>> man? Um, su shout out to to to the guys
um on and off the field. Um, obviously
man, the coaching staff did a great job,
but continue to lead the players in
being themselves. Obviously, play within
the scheme, but be you. Um, play to your
skill set, play your ball. Um, we know
who you was before you got here.
Obviously want to polish you up and
continue lead you in the direction of
getting the gold jacket and getting a
Lombardi trophy. So, um, that's always
appreciated, man. And, um, I think
everything else was just building off
the confidence and snowballing effect
for sure. um believing that you are the
elite talent that you that you were
perceived to be and that you believe
yourself. Um so um getting a chance to
stack on that and and continue to roll
um man it was everything and more for me
and my career. So I'm excited to keep
building on. I'm excited to keep playing
next to dogs that have helped that for
sure. And um I think it's much more to
see for sure.
>> And self-belief and that confidence is
easier said than done, right? Especially
when you have been through highs and
lows. Do you feel like you've gotten
that part down? that self-confidence
that they tried to instill in you.
>> Yeah. No, for sure. Um I believe it was
always there. Um obviously, um I think
early in the career, um it kind of got
foreshadowed a little bit, man. Just
trying to fight through some adversity
and understanding just the league in
general and just how to keep grinding
and fighting no matter what comes your
way. So, um once the opportunity
presented itself again, I knew to take
it and run with it and never look back.
And um that was just everything that I
needed. Um, and I super shout out to my
support system and my lovely lady. Um,
my mom, my grandparents continue to
believe in me and continue not letting
me put my head down and view myself any
other way than I that we originally
viewed me. So, um, I think it's been
everything and more um, coming into who
I am now. And I think it's going to
continue to build and I know Dan Quinn
um D Jones man PG sy to make sure that's
on a high um continue to try to to build
with that and I think it's it's the sky
is the limit for sure and each year it
seems as if in your career you have
found improvement especially these last
few years I believe five sacks with the
Raiders then again seven and a half.
What is that preparation like for you
like during this time because now you
got the bag right? So now it's offseason
work. It's time to put in that work.
What is that preparation like for you
and how has that materialized into the
success you found on the field?
>> Yeah, man. Um, finding that consistency
um with your with your schedule and your
life and your career was the biggest
thing for me, man.
>> Um, man, investing into your body,
investing into uh being careful with
your time and what you invest with. Um,
it's it's been huge for me. So, I think
obviously, man, the Raiders um that
transition um to get my feet wet and
just get to to just get a breath of
fresh air and get going. Um, that was
the start of something special. And last
year, man, be able to get seven and a
half during the season and get another
three during the postseason and and make
gamechanging plays and and be the guy
that the team can look forward to when
that game is called upon in those
crucial moments to to make a play and
give us their right spark to to turn the
game around. Um, I love those moments. I
love everything that came with it. Um,
but I do I do know that that wasn't just
from that moment. That was from
everything we prepared in offseason,
>> spring, training camp, and all
throughout the year. The consistency
even when you don't see through the
smoke. Um, continue to believe in it,
continue to pour into it. Um, and let
the big man above handle it. And, um,
I'm for sure that all his plans above,
it's in every favor for sure.
>> Amen. Amen. And when you have a season
like you had, this team's calling you.
This defense is saying, "Hey, we need
you a part of this." What makes you say,
"I want to go to a Donte Jones system, a
guy that is a firsttime defensive
coordinator." What were those
conversations like with him? What about
what you anticipate he does with this
defense made you say, "You know what?
This is the home for me."
>> No, no, that's facts. Um, man,
watching that Minnesota defense last
year, um, him him being a part of that.
I would just tell you, man, I got a
chance when I was watching the Detroit
game, um, it was so imposing as a
defense, man, when offense can't do
anything. And that's and that's a pretty
that's a pretty nice offense, you know,
skill skills on all front line
receivers, running back, quarterback,
everybody um is either tier two, tier
one level on on that offense. So um
watch how they impose their will on them
and that and that offense couldn't do
anything and you continually enforce it
all four quarters, eliminating their
playoff chances throughout the game,
man. Um that was huge. Um just seeing
how the energy that those guys play
with, the love that they have for each
other. Um, regardless, somebody made a
DB made a play and you see a D lineman
running down to the DB. Yeah.
>> And celebrating, doing a handshake. You
seeing guys on the sideline pumped every
nobody sitting down. Everybody's kind of
in tune to the game. Um, that show you
that the love that was within that
building um everything within that
culture that um Donte was a part of and
he knows what will be um the deciding
factor to taking this defense to an
elite level. So, um I was excited to be
a part of it. I believe that I'm
everything and more that this defense
can use and and take to be on the an
elite level
>> and um that's what we'll do this year.
>> Yeah. And this is a new look defense. A
lot of new pieces, but you said
something imposing your will. How do you
impose your will when you're on that
field facing those offenses?
>> Yeah. Um you got to you got to decide to
block me all four quarters. Um and
that's my favorite part about it. And
I'm willing to take it a fifth quarter
if it has to go there. So,
>> um I like that part about it. Um I I
never quit. I can go all day long. Um
the the the mindset and the energy that
I play with. Um it's now or never for
me. Um I don't believe there is a
another opportunity when I get on that a
chance to get on that field. Um I've
been a part of of being released. I've
been a part of having an injury and not
be able to play football. Um I've been a
part of watching games um week one and
and not being on the field and and
really be believing that, hey, I'm
supposed to be out there. I know I'm
that guy. I know I'm ready. I know um
God put us in this position for a
reason. So um I didn't seen it from all
perspectives. Um and I appreciate it.
Don't get me wrong. I I enjoy the
journey. I believe it's everything and
more to who I who I am and who I am to
become as a man and as a player. And um
it's exciting, man. It's exciting to be
a part of something like this and watch
yourself grow and and continue to
believe in something bigger than
yourself, obviously. Um whether that's
your faith um whether that's within the
coach and the team and most importantly
man um I think it's God man. I think he
continues to work his way and um you
just got to have control of what you
control and have all belief and faith in
him.
>> And and coach Jones prides himself on
having versatile defenders. How do you
fit that mold? Yeah, I think I think um
we have a lot of talent on this team
that can do a lot of different things
>> and um even when you're doing the
scouting report, you got to understand
that this guy may be known as a rusher,
but he also can drive moving coverage.
Um, he also can can do some stunts and
move in different ways, play inside and
kind of give you that that that mind
trickery to to go in throughout the game
and just hopefully understand that they
may play this one system all game, but
there's a possibility that they can
change up and do a lot more different
things than what they really do. So, um,
that's going to be huge um, for us, man.
We got a lot of a lot of talented guys
that can do so much. So, I'm happy to be
a part of that,
>> my boy. Man, it's great to have you
here, man. Congratulations on
everything. Kavon Chasan in the building
here to be one of our new edge wrestlers
to this new look defense. Man, I'm so
excited to see you out there, man.
Again, congratulations on all of your
success and now you got a home here in
the Burgundy and Gold. You damn right.
We love that Cavanis family. This is
Next Man Up. Part of Free Agency Fridays
here with Kavon Chson. You're going to
be hearing that name a lot in Northwest
Stadium. You know it. Yeah.